export const PHYSICSA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. In collision between two objects, kinetic energy is conserved only if",
A: "one of the objects was initially at rest",
B: "potential energy is converted to work",
C: "the collision is inelastic",
D: "the collision is elastic",
answer: "D. the collision is elastic",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The quantity of motion of a body is its",
A: "acceleration",
B: "displacement",
C: "mometum",
D: "velocity",
answer: "C. momentum",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The volume of a fixed mass of a gas varies inversely as the pressure on it provided the temperature is constant. This statement is",
A: "Pressure law",
B: "Charles law",
C: "Boyle's law",
D: "General gas law",
answer: "C. Boyle's law",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. An image formed on a screen is always",
A: "inverted",
B: "magnified",
C: "upright",
D: "virtual",
answer: "A. inverted",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. How would the capacitance of a parallel plate capacitor be affected if the distance of separation of its plates is decreased? It will",
A: "increase in value",
B: "decrease slightly",
C: "remain unchanged",
D: "drop to zero",
answer: "A. increase in value",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following machines does not apply the lever principle?",
A: "Claw hammer",
B: "Wheelbarrow",
C: "Single pulley",
D: "sugar tong",
answer: "C. Single pulley",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The average distance moved by a molecule between collisions is called",
A: "molecular distance",
B: "intermolecular distance",
C: "mean distance",
D: "mean free path",
answer: "D. mean free path",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following waves requires a material medium for its propagation?",
A: "Radio waves",
B: "Light waves",
C: "Sound waves",
D: "X-rays",
answer: "C. Sound waves",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The depolarising agent in a Leclanche cell is?",
A: "carbon  rod",
B: "ammonium chloride",
C: "manganese (IV) oxide",
D: "zinc plate",
answer: "C. manganese (IV) oxide",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The material used to slow down the neutrons in a nuclear reactor is",
A: "boron",
B: "copper",
C: "graphite",
D: "uranium",
answer: "C. graphite",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following statements explain why hot soapy water is more effective in cleaning oil-stained dishes?",
A: "The oil on the dishes repels the soap",
B: "soap and heat decrease the surface tension of oil",
C: "soap increases the surface tension of oil and water",
D: "Hot water increases the surface tension of oil",
answer: "B. soap and heat decrease the surface tension of oil",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The diagram above illustrates a beam of parallel rays from a distant object O, incident on one side of the total reflecting prism. Which diagram does not represent the correct path of the beam when it emerges from the prism?",
A: "W",
B: "X",
C: "Y",
D: "Z",
answer: "A.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. An electrical device has 50 turns in its primary coil be an",
A: "step-up transformer",
B: "step-down transformer",
C: "d.c generator",
D: "a.c generator",
answer: "C. d.c generator",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The earpiece of a telephone handset converts energy from",
A: "electrical to sound",
B: "sound to electrical",
C: "sound to electrical",
D: "sound to radio wave",
answer: "A. electrical to sound",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Two identical cups containing the same volume of water at 45°C and 5°C, are left in a room at 25°C. Which of the following graphs correctly illustrates the variation of temperature with time?",
A: "A",
B: "B",
C: "C",
D: "D",
answer: "D.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A ray of light travelling from glass into ethyl alcohol is incident at the boundary at an angle of incidence 3°. Calculate the angle of refraction. [Refractive index of glass =1.5; refractive index of ethyl alcohol = 1.36]",
A: "27°",
B: "33.5°",
C: "51.7°",
D: "72.8°",
answer: "C. 51.7°",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A 60kg man stands on a weighing balance in an elevator. If the elevator accelerates upwards at 5ms−2, determine the reading of the scale. [g = 10ms−2]",
A: "300N",
B: "600N",
C: "800N",
D: "900N",
answer: "D. 900N",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The length of an iron bar is 100cm at 20°C. At what temperature will its length increase by 0.01%? [Linear expansivity of iron = 1.2 x 10−5°C]",
A: "48.0°C",
B: "38.0°C",
C: "28.3°C",
D: "23.0°C",
answer: "C. 28.3°C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A moving-coil galvanometer which gives a full-scale on deflection with 0.005A is converted to a voltmeter reading up to 5V using an external resistance of 975Ω. What is the resistance of the metre?",
A: "0.25Ω",
B: "2.50Ω",
C: "25.00Ω",
D: "250.00Ω",
answer: "C. 25.00Ω",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A beam consisting of α-particles. β-particles and γ-rays pass through a magnetic field at right angles to the direction of the field. Which of the following observations would be made about the α-particles, β-particles, and γ-rays respectively?",
A: "Deflected, deflected, deflected",
B: "Deflected, deflected, not deflected",
C: "Deflected, not deflected, deflected",
D: "Not deflected, deflected, deflected",
answer: "B. Deflected, deflected, not deflected",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A parallel plate capacitor is charged and the charging battery is subsequently disconnected. lf the plates of the capacitor are moved farther apart by means of insulating handles, the",
A: "capacitance would increase",
B: "capacitance would decrease",
C: "charge on the capacitor would increase",
D: "charge on the capacitor would decrease",
answer: "A. capacitance would increase",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The velocity of sound in air at 15°C is 35400ms−1. Calculate the velocity at 47°C",
A: "790ms−1",
B: "602ms−1",
C: "358ms−1",
D: "322ms−1",
answer: "C. 358ms−1",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the current-voltage characteristics shown below is that exhibited an ohmic conductor?",
A: "A",
B: "B",
C: "C",
D: "D",
answer: "B.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A 500N box rests on a horizontal floor. A constant horizontal force is exerted on the box so that it moves through 8m. If the coefficient of kinetic  friction between the floor and the box is 0.22, calculate the workdone on the box",
A: "880J",
B: "440J",
C: "400J",
D: "110J",
answer: "A. 880J",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The diagram illustrates a ball of mass m sliding down a plank inclined at an angle of 0 to the horizontal. The kinetic friction between the ball and the plank is F and acceleration of free fall is g. The normal force on the ball is?",
A: "mgsin θ",
B: "mgtan θ, mgcos θ",
C: "mgcos θ",
D: "mgcot θ",
answer: "C. mgcos θ",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The diagram above illustrates a ball of mass m sliding down a plank inclined at an angle of 0 to the horizontal. The kinetic friction between the ball and the plank is F and the acceleration of free fall is g. The net force on the ball along the plank is?",
A: "mgsin θ + F",
B: "F - mgcos θ",
C: "mgsin θ - F",
D: "F + mgcos θ",
answer: "C. mgsin θθ – F",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. What factors determine the frequency of a note emitted by a vibrating string?",
A: "Amplitude of vibration, force constant of string and length of string",
B: "Amplitude of vibration, force constant of string, and tension in string",
C: "Mass per unit length of string, tension in string and length of string",
D: "Force constant of string, tension in string, and length of string.",
answer: "A. Amplitude of vibration, force constant of string and length of string",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The magnitude of the force experienced by a charge of 1.6 x 10−8C in a uniform electric field of intensity 5 x 105NC−1  is",
A: "3.2 x 10−14N",
B: "8.0 x 10−13N",
C: "8.0 x 10−3N",
D: "3.1 x 1013N",
answer: "B. 8.0 x 10−13N",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. A motorcycle starting from rest is uniformly accelerated such that its velocity in 10s is 72kmhr−1. What is its acceleration?",
A: "108ms ²",
B: "86ms ²",
C: "4ms ²",
D: "2ms ²",
answer: "D. 2ms2",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The temperature of an object is raised by 120°C. The resulting increase in its absolute temperature is",
A: "50K",
B: "120 K",
C: "200K",
D: "393K",
answer: "B. 120 K",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following statements about the motion of a simple pendulum is true?",
A: "It is a simple harmonic motion when the angle of displacement is large",
B: "It passes the equilibrium position with minimum speed",
C: "It possesses maximum kinetic energy at the extreme positions",
D: "lt swings faster at the poles than at the equator",
answer: "D. lt swings faster at the poles than at the equator",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. An electron of mass m and charge e moves in a circular path in a magnetic field of flux density B. How long does it take to complete one orbit?",
A: "2me/Bπ",
B: "2B/meπ",
C: "2πm/Be",
D: "Be/2πm",
answer: "A. 2me/Bπ",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following statements about photoelectrons is correct?",
A: "A faint green light produces photoelectrons with less kinetic energy than a bright red light",
B: "A red light releases a smaller number of electrons than a green light",
C: "A faint green light produces photoelectrons with greater kinetic energy than a bright red light",
D: "A red light produces more photoelectrons than a green light",
answer: "B. A red light releases a smaller number of electrons than a green light",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The sketched graph above illustrates the heating curve of a 0.02kg of water. Determine the approximate value of the specific latent heat of vapourization of water",
A: "2.25 x 106 J kg−1",
B: "4.17 x 103 J kg−1",
C: "2.00 x 103 J kg−1",
D: "1.00 x 103 J kg−1",
answer: "D. 1.00 x 103 J kg−1",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. In the hydraulic press, the force F applied is related to the diameter d of the cylinder by",
A: "F α d2",
B: "F α d",
C: "F α d−1",
D: "F α d−2",
answer: "A. Fαd2",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. In an electric circuit, an inductor of inductance 0.5 H and resistance 50Ω is connected to an alternating current source of frequency 60 Hz. Calculate the impedance of the circuit.",
A: "50.0Ω",
B: "450.5 Ω",
C: "195.0 Ω",
D: "1950.1 Ω",
answer: "C. 195.0 Ω",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following statements correctly explains why a total solar eclipse would be seen by people on only a small portion of the earth's surface? The",
A: "moon is larger in diameter than the earth",
B: "earth is larger in diameter than the sun",
C: "earth revolves around the sun",
D: "earth is larger in diameter than the moon.",
answer: "C. earth revolves around the sun",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Water waves have a wavelength of 3.6cm and speed of 18cms−1 in deep water. If the waves enter shallow water with wavelength of 2.0cm, calculate the speed of the waves in the shallow water.",
A: "0.4cms−1",
B: "2.5cms−1",
C: "10.0cms−1",
D: "10.8cms−1",
answer: "A. 0.4cms−1",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. An a.c. generator can be converted to a d.c. electric motor by replacing the",
A: "slip rings with a split ring and connecting a battery",
B: "split ring with slip rings and connecting a battery",
C: "a.c. with d.c. source and connecting slip rings",
D: "a.c. with d.c. source and connecting split rings",
answer: "A. slip rings with a split ring and connecting a battery",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. A ray of light travels obliquely from a less dense medium to a denser medium. Which of the following statements is true about the light?",
A: "The wavelength of the light increases in the second medium",
B: "The speed of the light increases in the second medium",
C: "The light refracts towards the normal",
D: "There Is a change in the frequency of the light",
answer: "C. The light refracts towards the normal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. An electron of mass 9.1x 1031 kg is travelling at a speed of 2.0 x 106ms−1. Calculate the associate wavelength of the electron. [h = 6.6. x 1034 Js]",
A: "3.63 x1010 m",
B: "3.63 x 10−8 m",
C: "3.63 x 10−7 m",
D: "6.89 x 10−4 m",
answer: "A. 3.63 x1010 m",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following statements about the process of melting of a solid are true? The temperature of the solid will  \nI. remain steady until melting starts. \nll. keep rising until melting starts, \nIII. remain steady as melting proceeds.  \nV. keep rising as melting proceeds.",
A: "II and llI only",
B: "IlI and IV only",
C: "I, Il and Ill only",
D: "ll and IV only",
answer: "B. IlI and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. A diver steps off a diving platform that is 10m above the water. If there is no air resistance during the fall, there will be a decrease in the diver's",
A: "gravitational potential energy",
B: "total mechanical energy",
C: "kinetic energy",
D: "momentum",
answer: "A. gravitational potential energy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following actions would increase the electric force between two positively charged particles?",
A: "Decreasing the mass of the particles",
B: "Decreasing the distance between the particles",
C: "Increasing the assistance between the particles",
D: "Increasing the mass of the particles",
answer: "B. Decreasing the distance between the particles",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. A luminous object is one that",
A: "gives off dim blue-green light only in the dark.",
B: "gives out light of its own",
C: "shines by reflected light only",
D: "glows only in the presence of light",
answer: "B. gives out light of its own",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following units is not fundamental?",
A: "Metre",
B: "Kilogram",
C: "Joule",
D: "Candela",
answer: "C. Joule",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The vacuum between the double walls of a thermos flask reduces heat loss through",
A: "conduction and radiation",
B: "convection and conduction",
C: "radiation only",
D: "conduction only",
answer: "B. convection and conduction",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. In photoelectric effect, the number of electrode emitted per second from a metallic surface is proportional to the",
A: "intensity of the incident radiation",
B: "frequency of the incident radiation",
C: "energy of the incident radiation",
D: "work function of the metal.",
answer: "A. intensity of the incident radiation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. When two cells of negligible internal resistances and equal e.m.f. denoted by E1 and E2 are connected in parallel, combined e.m.f. E is given by",
A: "E = E1 + E2",
B: "E = E1/E2",
C: "1/E = 1/E1 + 1/E2",
D: "E = E1 = E2",
answer: "A. E = E1 + E2",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following statement about viscosity is not true? it",
A: "depends on areas of the surfaces in contact",
B: "occurs in fluids",
C: "is independent of the relative velocity of the layers",
D: "depends on the tangential force between the layers",
answer: "A. depends on areas of the surfaces in contact",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]